3645 Welbourn Road

Apt 434 Bryan, TX

Sean Daniel Davis <u>s.davis@tamu.edu</u> 214-799-7708 Texas A&M University 400 Bizzell St College Station, TX

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

After graduating, I desire to elevate my skills and serve within my country, creating easy to use, reliable software that inspires real change in the way people live. I am driven to accomplish my goals and strive to surpass people's expectations of me. My favorite job experience has been teaching people and helping to solve practical problems within my community. I hope to use this opportunity to learn crucial technical skills and meet new people around the world.

### **EDUCATION**

Texas A&M University (3.825)

Computer Science, m. Cyber Security

Stephen F. Austin High School (3.76) Graduated Summa Cum Laude

Top 10% of graduating class with honors

College Station, TX

05/2023

Sugarland, TX

05/2019

### **COURSEWORK**

- Analysis of Algorithms (C++)
- Computer Systems
- Programming Studio (Python, CSS, JS, HTML, PHP, MySQL)
- Data Structures (C++)

- Discrete Structures and Mathematics
- Programming Languages (Scheme, Java)
- Computer Organization(HDL,ASM)

# **SKILL SET**

#### **Technical Skills**

- C++
- Java
- JavaPython

- CSS
- JavaScript
- HTML

- React JS
- Linux/UNIX

## **Professional Skills**

- Team Management, Teaching, and Interpersonal Communication
- Debugging and Troubleshooting and Code Review

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Telemundo Houston | KTMD** Dec 2020 – January 2021

Computer Engineer / IT Intern 40 hours

- Analyzed the anatomy of a cyber-attack and defense in the field of TV broadcast
- Maintain servers and software for news broadcast, including systems used by 40 instation editors and managers (Unity, Stratus editing, KVM, Dejero encode/decode)
- Learned life cycle of an IP address in computer networking and broadcast
- Maintained and deployed new technology to associates including cellular phones, laptops, TV station cameras, video encoding boxes

Texas A&M University July 2020 – Present

Teaching Assistant for Discrete Structures 10 hours

- Taught and assisted engineering students through one on one sessions to understand Discrete Structure and Analysis of algorithms
- Developed a higher level of understanding of analysis of algorithms through peer teaching

### **Home Depot** April 2020 – August 2020

Deliveries Associate

- Prepared and delivered 10 deliveries of lumber and concrete onto delivery trucks from the warehouse every day
- Interacted with and grew personable skills with customers in customer service center

### **KEY PROJECTS**

TV Station Equipment Upgrade – Telemundo Inc.

- Installed chipsets into all new station cameras allowing them to store video and be used by emergency first responders for quicker broadcast
- Deployed new phones, connecting 28 field reporters to the corporate network, equipped with faster data chips and more reliable internet connection for emergency broadcasts

**Sneeze** – *Texas A&M Game Developers* 

• Worked with 2 other developers to fully deploy a small video game called "Sneeze" from start to finish. *Responsibilities*: movement mechanics, path tracking and AI movement.

A/V Installation – Brian Consolidated

- Installed and tested 3 sound systems for different high school graduation ceremonies
- Ran live sound at event and learned audio mixing and effects

### **ACTIVITIES AND HONORS**

Engineering Team Lead – Intro to Engineering 2019

- Served as a project lead for a Python based video game with 4 developers
- Developed a video game closely resembling popular Japanese RPG "Pokémon"

**Project Member** – Aggie Coding Club 2020

• Contributed research and brainstorming for a project to build a custom voxel engine before COVID-19 ended the project.

**Drum Major** – Austin High School Band 2019

- Represented a band of 140 students at national conferences and competitions
- Taught students' intricate styles of marching and formations, as well as directing musical compositions

### REFERENCES

Philip Muller – Supervising Manager at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (281)-684-8678

**Melanio Polanco** – Co-worker at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (832)-306-8821

Marsha Gatling – Supervisor at Home Depot (Summer 2020)

• (281)-799-5743

**Treyton Zanutto** – Roommate / Informal Reference

• (832)-612-8546